I do not believe that any truly leftist
candidate [music] is genuinely trying to
win. I don't really care if say like
Bernie Sanders or AOC go home and
they're a secret Nazi. [music]
White people always show their ass. Your
job in Congress. It's not that I
magically [music] think you're going to,
you know, get the votes and like secure
meaningful change, but I do think your
presence exposes the failures of the
system to those who are darn aware of
it. We watch every election [music] this
like false narrative that we're somehow
doing a reset. It's not. This is a
continual [music] project of nonsense.
He says, you know, y'all calling me a
sellout. I am a sellout. I sold out
Yankee Stadium [music] three nights in a
row. And it's like, if I was in the
audience, I would have felt [music] so
crunchy in that moment. Like
the United States is not sovereign. And
that's the biggest lie. There there's an
interesting I've been thinking about
this a lot recently. this this this
question of sort of what's in the heart
and mind has come up. It it came up on a
recent episode with Glenn Greenwald. It
came up in a in a tweet by Emma Vigland
uh who said something along the lines
of, you know, I don't care if Graham
Platner is a secret Nazi. We'll put the
actual clip in here so I'm not represent
misrepresenting what she said.
something if he
>> should we just play it now because I if
you're going to react because I don't
want to I don't I'm not trying to
misrepresent anybody.
>> Here we go. I'll I'll pull it up.
>> You know, I've said this before. I don't
really care if say like Bernie Sanders
or AOC go home and they're a secret
Nazi, but they go out and they vote for
the right things. Like we're talking
about politicians as [laughter]
>> I mean FOR
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT. LIKE I'M LIKE
I'M LIKE THAT'S A I THINK THESE ARE THE
LINES that people are talking about.
Some people care about that exact thing.
>> White people always show they ass.
>> I mean so this is this is the question,
right? Like it's weird to watch how this
like what matters the idea that what
what someone does matters their actions.
>> Wait, go ahead. What was that?
>> No, go ahead. I'm sorry. Th this idea
that what people do matters than what's
matters more than what's in their hearts
and their mind is a concept that sort of
resonates with me, right? Because so
often the argument we get is like, well,
ASC really means well, so we shouldn't,
you know, look too much into the fact
that she says that she would support
Hakee Jeff as speaker or, you know, she
voted for the Iron Dome, but she didn't
really want to. And so I I'll say in a
in a weird parallel to what Emma's just
said, well, I don't really care about
what's their heart and and mind, what
you did was vote for an Iron Dome. But
there's this perverse way that that's
being flipped here where it's the the
reason that I don't care. I I will value
someone's actions over their internal
feelings. It's because that there's a
there's like a process that happens in
out where people's
desires don't always manifest in life
because of external factors. But if you
start with a malicious desire,
>> the idea external factors are going to
push you to in a more lefty direction is
bizarre. [laughter]
>> So let me tell you something, Brianna.
when I decided it was time to go back to
music, it was also because I felt like
when we when I was doing like the
analysis and geopolitically or, you
know, sociopolitically on I felt like I
was just like um kind of pruning trees.
And the more that I got to the root, I
realized, you know what the really
problem of all of this is? Everybody's a
[ __ ] liar. That's the problem is that
we live in a society that has now made
lying and dishonesty and inauthentic
authenticity not only acceptable but a
part of the process. So what Emma's
saying there is literally I don't care
if you're lying about who you really are
as long as you do the thing we want you
to do then simultaneously
lying to herself because that's not how
it works. Literally, it just doesn't
work that way.
>> What was that?
>> And and like we saw Fedman in real time
show us that,
>> right?
>> We didn't know that inside Federman was
a Nazi
>> and then he eventually showed when he
took off his enormous
sweatshirt that he is. [laughter]
So,
>> but also there were signs before, right?
Like part of what has been so
frustrating about people kind of ringing
the alarm bells of is gra is is platner
a secret Nazi is that sorry is is
platner sorry secretly Federman is that
even Federman wasn't secretly Federman.
There were people who said well it
wasn't great when he chased down that
black guy with a gun prior to winning
his election.
>> Yeah. There was a there was like a
citizen's arrest situation with
Federman. Um the fact that anyone he was
completely innocent or hadn't done
anything.
>> The fact that we were still moving past
>> like to your point
once there was even a
cons like a possibility that Graham
Platner was at some point in time a
Nazi, you're no longer viable. You're
off the table.
>> But here's the argument that gets made.
The argument that gets made is a lesser
of t evil argument which I know and
that's why we're
>> let's go back to your lyrics. [laughter]
>> But the argument that gets made is well
Susan Collins is obviously I mean she's
a Republican and we need to win the we
the Democrats need to win the Senate and
the the choice is already locked in.
This is this is what I was getting to
with the AOC stuff about like
pre-selecting her for 2028. It's like
the point at which we had an option to
avoid the lesser to evil is always way
in advance, right? It's now. It's now
when we could have a primary process
where we could vet candidates. And it
was back at the beginning when left
organizations, including the DSA, if
they saw themselves as a political party
who was recruiting candidates in the
same way that Justice Democrats say was
at a certain point, could have been
vetting their own triedand-true,
genuinely left candidate without all
these skeletons. But instead, we had
private individuals in their own
individual capacity selecting Graham
Platner. And I won't I don't want to
rehash this all because we went through
this in the um Shamasant episode, but
these people when asked by the Wall
Street Journal about the vetting
process, a lot of the stuff came up and
they decided to go for it anyway because
by their own admission superficially
they liked the idea of an oyster farmer
and a veteran who had a certain vibe who
also espoused Yes. good politics. He had
a goody elegy type behavior. That's what
that is. It sort of is. It's It sort of
is. And the the implication is that to
have the good platform that Platiner had
required all this other baggage. And
they they short circuit your brain the
same way they do in the in the in the
presidential primaries out of the idea
that it's not you don't have to pick
between two evils that we could make a
different decision a priority. We could
pick different kinds of candidates a
priority where you don't feel like you
have to hold your nose and vote for
Hillary Clinton and hold your nose and
vote for Joe Biden and hold your nose
and vote for Kla Harris. But what they
do is they obscure everything during the
decision-m process and then call us
somehow like tell us that we're the
problem for not wanting to play the game
that they've already pre-rigged. Okay.
So, you know how nonprofits are a fraud?
Yes. [laughter]
I mean yes I mean in what way do you
mean it? Well, namely because in
majority of cases they can't exist
without the problem subsisting
subsisting, right? So they don't often
times actually seek to solve the problem
because once that problem is solved then
there's no use for them. So I mean there
are many other ways that they are
fraudulent but that is one that is what
you're describing like
>> if you solve it if you solve the issue
of the two of the two sides etc etc of
the lesser of two evils then you
actually have to do something then
something actually has to happen. You
you you end up removing an entire
crux of folks who have built their whole
existence on
trying to find another. And we are in a
time again and I will say this again. I
do not believe that any truly leftist
candidate is genuinely trying to win
because there's no way to be a leftist
in the Senate, in Congress, or in the
president or as a president or in his
cabinet. There is no way to do that in
the current existence of the United
States. It is completely
counterintuitive, counterrevolutionary.
And again, well, not again because I
didn't say this before, but the United
States is not sovereign. And that's the
biggest lie is folks acting like this is
some, you know, place that's making
decisions on its own and, you know, that
Trump is sitting somewhere at night
getting inspiration during his REM sleep
and then waking up and saying, "We're
going to do this thing." like that's not
that's just not the reality of where we
are. And until we are willing to
actually address that reality, we're
going to keep talking in circles because
we're going to keep pruning branches in
instead of getting to the root. And the
root is is that the United States and
this whole electoral process that we
have really really like sunk our teeth
into and you know really committed
ourselves to changing is actually not
the true problem. That is the thing
that's put in front of us. The true
problem is the world banking system and
the IMF. This is a global issue. The
United States is just not just but the
United States has been used in the same
way that England was used to be a
colonizer and Israel has been its
laboratory in order to create the
weapons that continue to fund the ways
in which these control systems go. And
until we actually connect the dots
outside of here, we're just we're just
keeping ourselves entertained. It's just
instead of doing the bread and circuses
with football, we're doing the bread and
circuses with politics. And I know that
because these people be [ __ ]
performing. I was an actress. I am an
actress. I know a performer when I see
one. And listen, JD Vance deserves a SAG
award. [laughter]
Yeah. I mean I I I when you were talking
about sort of the self-defeating, you
know, the performativity of it all, I
was thinking about, you know, Shamasan,
who was running for uh Congress in
Washington as, you know, she's a
socialist, was the first elected
>> socialist in like a hundred years. And I
sometimes get challenged in the comment
section, well, why do you even care
about any electoral project? And I think
that participating in these elections
and even being elected and being in
Congress has the potential to heighten
the contradictions to in your in your
phrasing sort of do some of the pruning
to expose the root. To me, your job in
Congress is not it's not that I
magically think you're gonna, you know,
get the votes to like secure meaningful
change, but I do think your presence
exposes the failures of the system to
those who are
not able to be aren't aware of it
because they're locked in a corporate
media environment for all the reasons
why propaganda is so effective in the
United States, including the fact that
they there's apparently like a um uh
they put the kaibos in revolutionary
music like 30 years ago.
>> Yeah.
>> That being said, I would love to have an
opportunity for elected progressives. I
mean, I I'm not immune to being excited
by the possibility that elected
progressives could actually vote as a
block and gum up the Democrats agenda
the same way that Mansion and Cinema did
for corporate interest if and when
Democrats retake Congress in the fall.
>> Why? And I want to play well I want to
play a clip for you because I mean this
is the crux of why sorry not sorry force
the vote I think what is such an
animating issue and was such a a
divisive issue on the left because the
establishment left seemed seemed from my
perspective to run cover and make
excuses for squad members who chose not
to use the leverage that they had to
basically hold Congress hostage in
exchange for whatever demands the left
wanted to make. And that the the the
more of them there are and the narrower
the margins in the house are, the more
obvious it is that their project isn't
in fact to gum up the works for change,
but to create the veneer that there is a
possibility of slow incrementalism to
change the world and to distract us into
that particular project and and away
from more radical projects. So I want to
play a clip for you um that came out
recently. It's AOC talking to Cintita
Jackson, Re Reverend Jesse Jackson's
daughter on her radio show. Um, and it
was interesting to me because it seem
she seems to imply in this clip that she
understands the value of voting on a
block in a way that seemed anathema to
her uh in 2021 during force of vote. I
want to see if you are reading this the
same way.
>> So when you hear the corporate Democrats
tell you to get out of the party, what
say you? because you're a Democrat.
>> You can't tell them to get out and then
in a presidential cycle tell them that
they have an obligation to vote for you.
We're either a team or we're not. And at
the end of the day, we need we all need
each other to our chagrin and to our
disagreement
and to to our you know great
inconvenience.
All of us have to accept the reality
that we need each other whether we like
it or not. And you can't tell people to
leave when you need them at the end of
the day. And and and guess what? Look at
the point that we're at right now. You
know, hopefully in November, we're going
to be winning, Democrats are going to be
winning a majority that that is healthy
and sizable. But if you look at this
present moment, the House majority both
last cycle and this cycle was a
difference of four to five seats. Okay?
There are now going to be four to five
Democratic Socialists serving in the
next term. So if you tell us to go that
we can't associate with the Democratic
Party, all of a sudden that's your
majority right there.
>> So whether we like it or not, we need
one another. We shouldn't be talking
about going our separate ways because we
can't survive without a majority. And
that goes in both directions. We're
going to have to figure it out. Frankly,
that's that I think is um is the first
piece of it. And secondly, you know, I
think um uh you know, when I first
arrived to the house, it was I I you
know, I I met I was met with a
tremendously hostile environment.
>> And um and it was obviously very clear
that we were not welcome there. And they
wanted to make us all, you know, they
want to make me a one-term
congresswoman. they wanted to make many
others I think a one-term congresswoman
whether that's Ilhan Omar Rashida Tali
or whomever um but I think that you know
the attitude that I have taken to this
over time is that on our end you know
when this hostility comes towards us we
can respond with hostility in kind we
can respond with defensiveness
But I think
what I have learned over time is that I
just have responded with, "Okay, watch
us work.
>> Watch us work." And we'll go from 1 to 2
to 4 to 8 to 12 and people can go crying
and and and
you know be upset, but we'll just keep
growing.
>> Okay. So she understands leverage now.
She understands force to vote now. She
understands, she said that the margins
in the house are going to be slim and
that there will be four or five elected
progressives. By the way, that's the
same number we had back in 2021 with Cy
Bush and Jamal Bowman before they got
kicked out and Rashida Talib and Ilhan
Omar and AOC. The numbers were the same.
>> Yeah.
>> But back and the margins were similarly
slim.
And back then everybody acted like they
suddenly couldn't speak English when
Force of Vote was being explained to
them and the leverage was being
explained to them and they had every
excuse in the world about how
interpersonal disputes between
podcasters meant that they didn't want
to adopt the strategy. So now it seems
that she's saying very clearly either
the Democratic party we all vote
together and we win or we don't get
anything accomplished because you need
our votes. But then did you hear the
pivot
in the second half of that clip talking
about how she says, "Oh, well, when I
entered Congress, it was a very hostile
environment
>> environment."
>> And you have a choice about how to
respond to hostility. You could respond
in kind, which is how I would describe
force the vote and adversarial politics,
or we can just put our heads down and
grind through and work, get one or two
more every year. Exactly. We'll just one
by one
>> elect socialist Congress members, and
we'll slowly
>> take over Congress.
One of the things she said in there that
really just said to me, "This is why I
can't stand this broad." Um,
you know, when she's talking about first
term, you know, they wanted us to be
single term, etc., etc., etc.
I am of a mind that part of the reason
why we are not seeing any significant
change is because folks are trying so
hard to just keep coming back. they're
not willing to lose the seat and, you
know, to do the thing that pushes the
envelope that may end up pushing them
out. And it becomes where they're all
just trying to stay on the team. They're
trying to get drafted and stay on the
team. What can I do to stay on the team?
I'll switch positions. You know, I'll do
this. I'll do that. You know, remember
when she was crying about the Iron Dome?
It's like that was you switching
positions to stay on the team, mama.
Because if you were really bad about it,
you would have said, "Well, [ __ ] it, cuz
I just can't do this. like this ain't
the move and I refuse.
>> Yeah. Tell us what Pelosi said to you to
make you cry on the house floor. Let us
be on your side.
>> Yeah. No, she said I'll ruin to support
you.
>> I promise you that's what I believe she
said. I'll ruin you. Something to that
effect because at the end of the day,
this is not about the people. This is
about the parties. And no matter how
many podcasts
uh you know AOC goes on
to be to to to to show that she's down
with the people you know and she's she's
in the streets.
They are not serving
a they are not serving an effort at
creating pathways for change. They are
serving an effort at creating pathways
for possibility. And we all know who
have dated
potential that [laughter] you can't
book ticket on that. And that's what we
keep booking ticket on. And this is an
international issue. You know, I'm
talking to people in Kenya. I'm talking
to people in Grenada. And they're all
saying the same thing that every
election you have these folks who are
promising, I'm going to do this, that,
and the third. And then they don't. and
then they get in position and they do
the same thing which is align with a
colonizer whether it's France or England
or you know Israel or the US and sell
the people out and so we're watching it
in the US and thinking like this is the
only thing that's happening here however
it's not this is a rule book a playbook
that has been happening and the only
difference is that the Democrats just do
the Democrats just put a cold compress
on your back while they stab you like
that's the difference it's just it's
like I'm not going to stab you in your
back and break your leg you So, I don't
know. I I don't I AOC
>> I'm listening to her all of a sudden
understand, you know,
>> leverage
>> what it means to have leverage, which to
me is a very very basic concept. Um,
we've all been on a seessaw and
[laughter]
but it only matters now because it
matters now. And I want to add something
else, Briana,
when you were saying how,
you know, there's a role that folks can
play in Congress to shake the to shake
things up, right? To actually
demonstrate in real time like, see, this
looks crazy. I don't disbelieve that. I
simply believe that we are way further
along in the
catastrophe of this country than a lot
of us uh want to admit but also
that and and because of that we require
greater actions um we require stronger
um sentiments and that's why you know
Roana and get lambasted and mollywapped
by Jeremy Scill because
there there just really is not room in
the same way there has been to tow the
line to walk the line you know folks can
see so someone like AOC she's been doing
that for a long time and she's in my
opinion um she's not cut to do anything
other than that she is a Puerto Rican
Obama from the Bronx
Yeah, I I I feel as though I really take
the point that all of us might be moot.
I've joked on the podcast before that
I've been calling this last summer,
hashlast, which is kind of like yolo
vibes but darker because maybe it's the
last summer for all of us.
>> Correct.
>> Um just trying to stay present, living
my best life. Uh but but also like this
part to better understand
>> in his best life. Your makeup looks
[laughter] great.
>> Oh, thank you. I think it's Sorry, this
is a little peek behind the curtain.
When I ask guests to record between 1
and 4, it's not because that's like an
opening on my schedule. This is my job.
I have all day to record anytime you
want. But my theory is the best lighting
in my apartment is around 3 or 4:00
>> and that's what time it is recording.
[laughter]
I don't have
>> I wish I could recreate these conditions
>> today which is why I also look like a
ghost because the fires the wildfires in
Canada have I mean I moved from LA to do
this [ __ ] in New York. So the wildfires
from Canada have our skies a
orange tangerine hue and the uh air
quality is like unbreathable. So I'm
just here we are inside. Incredible. I I
I saw a little bit some some clips about
it on the internet. I This was happening
um it was when my 20th high school
reunion was. So this was 20 2023
and it almost got cancelled because of
the smoke coming down from Canada in New
York. I mean it's and it was
>> it's dense. Like I thought we were
having I thought every time something
like this happens I'm like are they
here? cuz I'm just like please
[laughter]
>> disclosure day.
>> So last summer it's all it's giving
those vibes. I'm like at the end of
parable of the se so sewer right now so
it's all feeling very um thematic. Here
it is actually on the book like very
very close to the end.
>> Oh you're
>> okay. But um just to close the the
circle on this Him Jeffrey's point real
quick because this sorry I just I have
to evangelize about this. Maybe I'll do
a radar about it but probably not. So
let me just get it out on the podcast
right now. People
have been frustrated and confused by the
choice of Zoro Mammdani and AOC in
particular to pre-endorse
Hakee Jeff for Speaker of the House.
That in
>> Yeah, that in conjunction with AOC's
statement here
>> um
gives me pause. She sets up a parallel
between how she was tweet treated by
then Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi
when she first entered Congress, which
to be clear, I was there covering it for
the interstep the first day. She started
with the Green New Deal uh sit in Nancy
Pelos's office and apparently was very
much
punished and and and shut down uh by the
establishment for having done that. Uh I
also implore people this this this five
and a half years almost six year project
at Bad Faith has really done its due
diligence. Go back and listen to Shri
Shriot Chakabat uh who and uh Corbin
Trent who both were working on her um
team at that time talk about
the backlash that she got over that here
on Bad Faith Podcast. Okay,
>> that happened to her. She she tried she
opened with a bang. She got shut down by
the establishment. She's now setting up
this idea that in this new version with
this current the new establishment
headed by Hakee Jeff things are going to
I can use leverage but and then she
turns it back into no we're not going to
be adversarial. We're going to do this
incremental approach where we can just
keep electing progressives and that's
what's going to change things. Now, I
had made the point that we have the
exact same number of elected
progressives now that we did in 2021,
five years ago, because remember, we
lost Cy Bush and Jamal Bowman, they got
knocked down by these Apac fights. And
while there is more resilience now in
large part because of
resilience that was paid for with
hundreds of thousands of Palestinian
lives and a genocide that galvanized
people around this issue and opened
people's eyes up to the evil of Apac.
>> Yeah. you know, and so that there's more
resil these candidates are more
resilient than they once were. Like, and
that is being used to make an argument
for incrementalism instead of it being
argued that this is why we need to up
the ante and change the tactics. And it
was very disheartening for me in that
clip to hear her sort of acknowledge all
of the true facts of the establishment
came out against her. You know, she was
punished for trying to take a stand for
something right and good. uh it is good
and right to use leverage and then
turn that into an argument for how she
should keep doing the thing that
obviously didn't work including
endorsing Hakeem Jeff who was going to
be the ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar
ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar ar
ar ar ar architect of her demise the
same way that Nancy Pelosi was. But that
is what makes her a Democrat.
Well, that's literally the hallmark of
being a Democrat. doing the same thing
over and over again expecting a
different result because your literal
role as a Democrat is to be false fake
phony opposition. So,
>> and the truth is a lot of the people
that are listening to you, not I won't
even say that the the truth is is that
many people won't go back and listen or
weren't listening 5 years ago and so
this is all new to them. So, this is a
whole new mistake to them. So that even
the pattern recognition isn't a isn't
even able to be addressed to point out
oh dang you are doing the same thing
again which is why we should not be
supporting you and you know when I am
trying to impart to people like hey
we're seeing the same thing over and
over again it's so much of it is really
just uh speaking into the ether because
they're like well I wasn't paying
attention back then so that doesn't
matter to me that's not true to me um
you know we are
>> watching
We watch every election this like false
narrative that we're somehow doing a
reset. It's not. It's this is a
continual project of nonsense of
discrimination of harm etc. We just put
different faces in front of it. It
doesn't reset. It doesn't recalibrate.
It literally continues. They may add
seats to the table. May they may take
seats away. Someone like AOC likes
sitting at the table even if she only
gets some of the sides. Like that's
really what it is. So that's the
hallmark of our government of the
Democrats. You know, they pride
themselves not on being for change. They
pride themselves on looking nice while
not advocating. Like that's Nancy Pelosi
kneelled in a Kente and I will never
ever ever get over [laughter] that in a
Kente stole. We wasn't asking for that.
We was asking for police immunity to be
ended and they said you know what we're
going to do though what we're going to
do. Okay. Yes. But also look at us Neil.
>> It's just optics.
>> You know at what point So at what point
then Briana do we get tired of saying
it's just optics? At what point do we
then say, "Okay,
this is insulting.
This is literally insulting you." Like,
like Jesse Jackson's daughter, I would
have loved for her to say on there,
"Quit insulting me." You know, AOC tried
to come for me on the internets and I
said, "Stop it. You don't
>> really?"
>> Yes. Because when she because when
>> because when Mahmud Khalo was was
released, she like ran up and was trying
to be in the pictures and it looked
crazy. Okay. And in the comments, it was
on BT News and in the comments I was
like, "Look at her doing the most. Like,
why is she doing all of this?" And then
she came in the comments like, "I was
there and I helped get him released,
etc., etc., etc." And it's like, the
fact that you still don't even see that
even if you did all of that, let this
man's release be this man's release.
Like, why are you running up on him and
his daughter and his wife to be in the
[ __ ] pictures? Because you're an
opportunistic,
corny politician liar. That's why. And
>> I do remember, so don't come for me.
>> I do remember the encampment folks uh
not wanting her to be there. I mean, and
I I trust the people who were running
the encampment, the students who were
being threatened in all the ways that
they were being threatened and obviously
Mahmud Khil being
>> um imprisoned for a year. And I I I
mean, I trust their perspective the
most. And if they didn't want her to be
there because they felt like it was a
photo op and that she wasn't advancing
the interest of the movement and this
was even before the tirelessly fighting
stuff, which she has yet to address at
the DNC, then I, you know, I credit I
credit their perspective on that.
Absolutely.
I it's I want to ask you taking it a
little bit back to the music stuff, but
staying on this theme of
the the performativity, the kinte cloth
of it all. I don't know if you caught
any of the brewhaha around Jay-Z's uh
recent concert in Madison Square Garden
where he freestyled about
>> calling. I remember I'm before all of
this. I'm a hip-hop head. Never forget
that. Okay. So you so you know you know
what I'm talking about.
>> So I have a new radio show every Friday
on Tabith Smiley's uh KBLA Talk 1580.
You can check me out. Summers.
>> So it's every Friday.
>> Really exciting.
>> Thank you. Every Friday uh 12 to 2 and 4
to 6 and you can download the KBLA Talk
1580 app to listen to it. And basically
Tavis was like just do whatever you
want. So uh that's what I do. And so I
recorded the first episode and I talked
about the Jay-Z verse and
this is yet another example of let's
just see how far we can take it. Let's
just see how far
>> Can you set it up for folks who don't
know what the verse was about? Should I
Should I pull it up?
>> Please pull it up. Yeah. So Jay-Z uh
performed a series of shows at Madison
Square Garden as a part of his like
comeback tour. He just released like a
limited edition of his first album,
Reasonable Doubt, with Target uh in the
midst of an ongoing black boycott of
Target that start that was sparked by
their removal of their DEI standards and
practices. And so Jay-Z uh he decided
against the best wish against his better
judgment in my opinion to then do this
deal with Target. And black folks have
been very loudly against this, right?
because it's been bubbling. You know,
the billionaire class, he is a part of
the billionaire class. He had he was at
that dinner that he was sitting at the
same table with Ivanka Trump and Jared
Kushner. Um he tried to get a he tried
to get a casino in Times Square. He had
been boasting about his um he had been
boasting about his ownership with the
Nets, with the Brooklyn Nets. And that
was the thing that made a lot of black
people who had been very adverse to the
building of the stadium finally say,
"Well, we don't want to get in the way
of a black man being owner in the NBA
only to find out that he only had 1%
ownership and that he was essentially
tokenized in order to manufacture their
consent." Right. And that's why he was
in the Epstein files as well. like not
he wasn't in them, but he was discussed
in them as playing exactly that role of
getting black people in line.
>> Well, he actually was in the Epstein
files as a uh cohort with Harvey
Weinstein in the effort to and the
successful effort to drug women and
sleep with them. So, he was in there as
well as um push a teeth from the clips
and
>> Well, what do you mean? I missed that.
So, he was described as being a part of
>> Yes.
So, um, then you have the fact that, you
know, after Colin Kaepernick is ousted
from the NFL and, you know, he's just
shamed and shaded for his, um,
resistance efforts by kneeling in the
support or in the challenging of police
brutality. Then you have Jay-Z who comes
into the NFL as like, yeah, you know,
they kicked you out, but I'm I'm I'm I'm
buddy buddy. Right? And so that's the
context here. There has been some
friction between him and Cap in stating
that basically Kaepernick stating that
like he feels Jay-Z sold him out, right?
Like Jay-Z going in there after the way
that NFL treated him like he didn't do
anything to like help his cause and he
also to my understanding um wasn't being
like a friend to Cap either. So that's
the context.
He also cut off his locks and is back to
a Caesar.
[laughter]
>> I think that's important to reflection
of his anti-revolutionary activities.
>> Yes, I do.
>> He's going to show up with a conchk
next. [laughter]
>> Yes.
A conchk and lim.
>> Okay. So, at the concert then he does a
freestyle that includes uh the following
lyrics. I am not a rapper, so I'm sorry.
Maybe we'll put a clip of the actual
thing in uh instead of me reading this,
but he says, "Buddy took a check. I
ain't even mad at him, but along with
that check, you have to sign a
non-disparagement. I'm the one they
can't control." So, the implication
being that Kaepernick is the sellout who
has, you know, allegedly signed a
non-disparagement.
>> Yes. Taken a check to not speak poorly
of the NFL when Jay-Z is
>> the real one. the one that can't control
>> when the truth that's not true by the
way. So Carrie Champion and um Jamal
Hill talk about it on their podcast and
Jamal Hill did a documentary about this
whole uh situation with Cap and the NFL
and she was like you know he talked all
I mean the whole documentary is him
talking [ __ ] about the NFL. So this is
just simply not true. I mean even if he
did sign an NDA he's not honoring it. So
there's that.
>> And then there was another part of the
freestyle where he basically says the
target boycott is fruitless because
you're not boycotting every single thing
in the world. Correct? Like didn't you
know that Meta was owned by you know
Facebook, Instagram was owned by Meta
and Google owns YouTube. So if you use
anything you're helping basically so
don't do anything at all. Right.
>> But he but but at the crux of that is
you guys are being hypocrites. And he
says, you know, y'all calling me a
sellout. I am a sellout. I sold out
Yankee Stadium three nights in a row.
And it's like if I was in the audience,
I would have felt so crunchy in that
moment. Like
>> I really gave this man my money,
>> you know, and think folks will set. And
then he also goes in in this verse, he
also boasts about, you know, helping
people get out of prison and that, you
know, being a part of um prison, you
know, justice, etc. or sorry um being a
part of
I guess justice reform again
if you're doing that while doing this
other thing it cancels it out if you're
sitting at lunch or at dinner with Jared
Kushner and you know and by the way that
dinner was the same organization that
does the the the uh criminal justice
reform so you're sitting at a table with
Beyonce, Jared Kushner, Ivanka Trump,
and I'm supposed to believe that y'all
are talking about criminal justice
reform.
>> Is is that what I'm supposed to believe?
And I think this is the thing that a lot
of us don't want to believe. But this
brings us back to the nonprofit sector
and to the philanthropic sector. And
that in many more in in more ways than
we would like to admit,
those spaces are not
altruistic.
They're not. They are often really just
little tide pools and back corners and
fronts for corporate entities and
interests to do what they want to do. Um
>> they're reputation laundering factories.
>> That's it. It's it's it's the nonprofit
version of I forgot what it's called.
You would know the name. Like when
>> um it's like pinkwashing. It's like the
corporate version of pinkwashing and
then it's like the corporate version of
Saudi Arabia getting involved in soccer,
right? and like trying to clean up their
image by being involved in sports. Uh it
it all ends up
>> again being a front. It is it it leads
me all the way back to what I was saying
before. We are in a deep mastrom
of
lies and it and the what makes them so
dangerous is it's ver similitude. It's
lies presented as truth, right? It's not
even being questioned in the way that it
used to be. It is really just an
assuming now that whatever is said is
said even when it is always even when it
is in the context or coming out the
voice of somebody who is known to be
disingenuous. And so I
I gotta tell you, Briana, at this point,
I've become far more
my politics has expanded beyond just the
political
>> because I feel like the the limitations
of the political are what has kept us
from not being able to truly have
effective resistance movements. Because
at the end of the day,
>> at the end of the day, if your politics
don't have
at the end of the day, if your politics
don't have some type of mysticism, some
type of spirituality, something bigger
attached to them, you're literally just
connected to something that is connected
to the thing you hate. And so when you
when that thing goes down, you go down
with it.
>> Hey YouTube, thanks [music] for
watching. Just a reminder that this is a
podcast. You can catch an extra premium
episode every Monday for $5 a month at
patreon.com/badfaithpodcast. [music]
That's patreon.com/badfaithpodcast
for $5 a month. An extra episode every
week. Additionally, please do consider
[music] liking this video, subscribing
to this channel. It helps us out. It
helps independent media beat the
algorithm. We appreciate you. [music]
And as always, keep the faith.